How to delete a node from a circle link lest.
Please pay attention for this tricky operation.
We have about four taps or four conditions that we should cover.
And while creating a method that delete a note from a circling of list, we have four cases, so we
will start by the first case.
If had equal equal to null, then return.
By the way, this method called delete note, it should pass that key as a parameter because we are
searching for a key that is presented in the linked list or not.
And we if it is presented, then we should delete this note this year present the value of the note
that we are searching for to the to be deleted.
The first case that we should cover if had equal equal to null, then return.
Consider this method called Delete Node 100.
We passed 100 to it.
And consider this circular link and list.
It is containing only one node and its reference to 1024.
As an address, so the head refers to this note.
It may contain one or more, but if had equal equal to null, then return if there is no notes inside
the circle and link at least considered the second case, if had equal to the head data, equal equal
to the key and had referred the knock next equal equal to had, then we are talking about a one less
one single note inside this list.
So free the head.
He laid the head and had equal to then not then the circle anchored list that it is containing only
one note.
Then delete this note and the head referred it equal to that.
None.
This is the second case.
So until now, we have covered and we have covered that.
If had equal to null, then return.
We don't have any notes.
The second case, if there is one note that it is contained in this circle or linked list and we need
to delete this note, then delete it and refer to the had equal to that not empty emptying this circular
link list.
The third case is.
If had data equal equal to that key.
If we found this key.
And along the notes.
And we need to delete it.
If had data equal equal to the key, so if we know that we are searching for equal to the note at the
beginning or that at that point there that it is referred to as head, then this will be the case.
OK.
Consider a normal link circle link atlas that contains many or three nodes, and we are going to delete
the first node because we are searching for a key that that is represented at the first node.
So consider a method called delete node and passing it perimeter at 100.
And we are executing this method along this circular link list.
OK.
We search for 100, but we found it directly that it was at the first note and this first note referred
for us as had so had data equal equal to the key.
Yes, this is the case.
So we are searching for 100 to delete it and.
The one it is found and the first note so struck note equal to last, though, create a new reference
last and create no doubt and refer it.
Does it tempt?
Move it to the next one.
So why last does next does not equal to had moved the last to the last of the and the end of the circle
and place and then equal to help create a team that is referred to head and remove that linkage?
OK, so remove the linkage from the first one does that and to then note that it is next to the.
First one, which is the second one.
OK, I will repeat it.
Moved ahead from the first because we need to delete the first and move the linkage between the last
and the first, delete this linkage and now remove that by using the stamp equal to head and remove
this and remove that down.
OK, so delete it now changed the references from 1024, which is deleted to 2024, which is the address
of the newly and newly a node that that is referenced as HAP.
So you see, guys, this is the algorithm behind deleting the circular link.
From first again, I would consider this node.
At the first suffering as the war had and last move at the last create attempt, according to ET.
Referring to 1024, which is the hebb remove the linkage.
Delete Stamp, which is referring to the guarantee ahead.
Now the head becomes the second note or the following note of the deleted one.
Therefore, change their addresses and the change that reference.
OK.
Now.
The forces tap or the force condition that we need to cover is deleting at a node that that is like
300.
This is a node that we are searching for 300 to delete it.
So consider we are executing a method and we passed 300 as a key.
So we start searching for 300 until we see that 300 refers to the next and then the last.
Then we are going to create the current current.
Is referring to the head and temp.
We have found it as which is the end.
Therefore, while we are referencing the temp to air, we move that current to to that one by one until
reaching temp.
The previous clip for ditching the temp by one by one.
And then we remove the linkage from the last through the first we remove it and we put the current from
current to the first.
Delete the 10 party and change the addresses.
And this is the linkage.
This is the trick behind deleting and circular link at this.
Best case scenario is deleting a note at the beginning, which is the head and the worst case scenario
is off and deleting a note at the end of their list.
The best-case scenario is deleting a note at the beginning, at the end, the end, because there's
only one note represented in circle and list.
So deleting and a single and the only one note represented in Circle Link at last.
But the worst case scenario is off and is deleting in note at the end of the list or any place.
Because we are, we are.
And we should change the references and go through all the nodes and the change the added friends of
the last note to be the one that previous and referenced at the beginning.
Now, let's go and see the circle and list.